A Guide to the Coach and Carriage Papers, 1794-1848
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Coach and Carriage Papers, 1794-1848, 1794-1809.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 80.2
13 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm (M-1585) and transcript (TR91).
Custodial History
Transferred to Special Collections from Architectural Research in 1980.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence between coachmakers and their customers containing descriptions, specifications, special modification requests, and some prices for new carriages, as well as modifications to and repairs of existing coaches and a request for the appraisal of two coaches to be sold second-hand. Also, the petitions from two Frederick County [probably Maryland] court cases between apprentices and master craftsmen (a saddler and a coachmaker). Letter, March 25, 1848, from coachmaker Isaac Mix, Jr., New York, to an unnamed customer. Other coachmakers mentioned include Messrs. Lukin and Allan and Mr. Leader, all English, and Cornelius Fur of Maryland. Other names appearing in the collection include: Daniel Buchias, Robert Edging, Otto McKusick, and Isaac Martz, all in America; and Gen. John William Egerton, Hon. Gen. Alexander Hope, Sir John Shelley, Duchess of Somerset, Duke of Somerset, Lord T. Spencer, and Hon. Thomas Steele, all in England.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Persons:
Buckias, Daniel.; Egerton, John William.; Fur, Cornelius.; Hope, Alexander, Sir, 1769- 1837.; Leader, Mr.; Lukin, Lionel, 1742-1834.; Martz, Isaac.; Mix, Isaac.; Shelley, John, Sir.; Somerset, Edward Adolphus Seymour, Duke, 1775-1855.
Subjects:
Apprentices-- Maryland--History--18th century.; Carriage and wagon making--England--History.; Carriage and wagon making--Maryland--History--18th century.; Carriage manufacturers and dealers--England.; Master and servant--Maryland--History--18th century.
Corporate Names:
Maryland. County Court (Frederick County); Lukin and Allan (Firm)
Genre and Form Terms:
Contracts--Maryland--18th century.; Court records-- Maryland--18th century.
Contents List
- Petition from Robert Edging, coachmaker's apprentice, Frederick County [Md.], vs Daniel Buchias, coachmaker, Frederick Town [Md.]. Requests that the court release Edging from his contract with Buchias. 2 pages, 20 March 1794.
- Petition from Isaac Martz, Frederick County [Md.], to Frederick County Court. Requests that the contract between Martz and Otho McKusick be dissolved. Includes note from the court dated 27 November 1794 dissolving the contract. 2 pages, 1794.
- Sir John Shelley, n.p., to Mr. Leader, coachmaker, Liquorpond Street, London. Orders a "very neat false lining" for his chaise and wishes to install harder cushions. 4 pages, 7 April 1795.
- Gen. John William Egerton, Grosvenor Square, London, to "Sir," Liquorpond Street, London. Discusses the receipt of the new coach; dislikes the carpet and wishes to make changes. Mrs. Egerton dislikes the inside handles. 4 pages, 12 May 1797.
- Memorandum of agreement between (?) Maquire, n.p., and Cornelius Fur of Maryland, that fur complete a wagon to Maquire's specifications within six weeks. Witnessed and signed by Conrad Fuss and Andrew Brackin. 2 pages, 11 October 1797.
- Hon. Thomas Stule, Dover, to "Sir," n.p. Discusses the specifications for a new coach; wants leather affixed permanently to the platform; believes Salisbury boots are out of fashion and does not want one; discusses the cloth lining of the coach. 4 pages, 8 October 1798.
- Duchess of Somerset, n.p., to Mr. Allen, n.p. Requests an appraisal of two coaches which are to be sold second-hand. 2 pages, 17 April 1803.
- Duke of Somerset, Piccadilly, London, England to Mr. Lukin, n.p. Requests repairs to the wheels and lamps of his curricle; wishes to have it done as soon as possible. 2 pages, 11 July 1806.
- Duke of Somerset, n.p., to Mr. Lukin, n.p. Requests a new hammercloth mantle, reins, and harness for his carriage; wants Mr. Lukin to call on him in the morning. 2 pages, 11 February 1807.
- Hon. Gen. Alexander Hope, n.p. to Mssrs. Lukin and Allan, coachmakers, Longacre, London. Discusses the purchase of a small phaeton that is for sale in Longacre; shall be in town Monday to pay for it. 2 pages, 27 November 1809.
- Isaac Mix Jr., New York, to [Dozell?], n.p. Discusses the receipt of two cane-seat carriages which he has not been able to sell; has sent a note for $350 to help meet the $500 due on March 28; needs help to meet the rest of the note; has written to Newark about the enamelled leather. 1 page, 25 March 1848.
- Lord T. Spencer, House of Commons, London, to "Sir", n.p. Discusses the new wheels for his carriage; hopes that they do not differ from the ones recommended by the House of Commons; has directed that a pattern wheel be made at his own expense. 4 pages, 3 March n.y.
- [?] Salisbury, n.p., to "Sir". Describes damage to his Landau; wants to know how long it will take to fix it. 2 pages, n.d.